Guide to the Mathew B. Brady and Levin Corbin Handy Photographic Studios Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Levin Corbin Handy Studio, 1849-circa 1956; Series II; (28 boxes)
  - Proof Books, 2 volumes containing 368 photographic prints
    - Proof Book of Portraits by the Mathew B. Brady Studio, circa 1900; 100 pages with 275 photographic prints
      - Leaf group No. 22, (21 photographic prints) (Box 16, Folder 634)
        - 1298 - No photographic print
          - Photographic Prints of Studio Portraits by the Mathew B. Brady Studio, (107 photographic prints)
            - Boyd, Belle, spy for the Confederate States of America (Box 18, Folder 643)
            - Broderick, David Colbreth, (2 photographic prints) (Box 18, Folder 644)
              United States Senator from California
            - Buell, Don Carlos (Box 18, Folder 645-646)
            - Buford, John, and his staff (Box 18, Folder 647)
            - Carlile, John Snyder (Box 18, Folder 648)
              United States Senator from Virginia and United States Representative from Virginia
            - Chapman, Miss (Box 18, Folder 649)
            - Cox, Jacob Dolson, Jr. (Box 18, Folder 650)
              Governor of Ohio and United States Secretary of the Interior
            - Curtis, George William (Box 18, Folder 651)
            - Cushman, Pauline, actress and spy for the United States (Box 18, Folder 652)
            - Dickinson, Anna Elizabeth (Box 18, Folder 653)
            - Douglas, Stephen Arnold (Box 18, Folder 654)
            - Edmunds, George Franklin (Box 18, Folder 655)
              United States Senator from Vermont
            - Elzey, Arnold, Confederate States of America (Box 18, Folder 656)
            - Fish, Hamilton (Box 18, Folder 657)
              Governor of New York, United States Senator from New York, and United States Secretary of State
            - Garfield, James Abram and Mary Garfield (Box 18, Folder 658)
            - Garrison, William Lloyd (Box 18, Folder 659)
            - Gatling, Richard Jordan (Box 18, Folder 660)
            - Gorman, Willis Arnold, and his wife, Martha Stone Gorman (Box 18, Folder 661)
            - Grant, Julia Boggs Dent, and Ellen "Nellie" Wrenshall Grant (Box 18, Folder 662)
            - Grant, Ulysses S. (Box 18, Folder 663-665)
            - Griffin, Charles, and his staff (Box 18, Folder 666)
            - Halleck, Fitz-Greene, poet (Box 18, Folder 667)
            - Hamilton, Morgan Calvin (Box 18, Folder 668)
              United States Senator from Texas
            - Harper Brothers, (2 photographic prints) (Box 18, Folder 669)
              Founders of Harper's Magazine, from left to right, Fletcher Harper, James Harper, John Harper, and Wesley Harper
            - Harris, David Bullock, Confederate States of America (Box 18, Folder 670)
            - Harris, Clara (Box 18, Folder 671)
              Daughter of United States Senator Ira Harris from New York and accompanied Abraham Lincoln the night of his assassination.
            - Hawthorne, Nathaniel, (3 photographic prints) (Box 18, Folder 672)
            - Hayes, Isaac Israel, Arctic explorer and physician (Box 18, Folder 673)
            - Healey, George Peter Alexander (Box 18, Folder 674)
            - Hodge, Charles, Dr., (3 photographic prints) (Box 18, Folder 675)
            - Holman, Julia, actress (Box 18, Folder 676)
            - Huger, Benjamin, Confederate States of America (Box 18, Folder 677)
            - Hunter, Robert Mercer Taliaferro (Box 18, Folder 678)
            - Imboden, John Daniel, Confederate States of America (Box 18, Folder 679)
            - Kautz, August Valentine, with an unidentified man on the left and Philip Henry Sheridan on the right (Box 18, Folder 680)
            - Kendall, Elizabeth Bright (Box 18, Folder 681)
            - Kershaw, Joseph Brevard, Confederate States of America (Box 18, Folder 682)
            - Kinsman, Seth, hunter and antler chair-maker (Box 18, Folder 683)
            - Lane, Joseph, (2 photographic prints) (Box 18, Folder 684)
              United States Senator from Oregon, Governor of Oregon Territory, and Delegate to the United States Representatives from the Oregon Territory
            - Lincoln, Abraham, (3 photographic prints) (Box 18, Folder 685)
            - Lincoln, Abraham, (4 photographic prints) (Box 18, Folder 686)
            - Lincoln, Abraham (Box 18, Folder 687-689)
            - Lincoln, Abraham, and Thomas "Tad" Lincoln, (3 photographic prints) (Box 18, Folder 690)
            - Lincoln, Mary Todd (Box 18, Folder 691)
            - Lincoln, Robert Todd, (2 photographic prints) (Box 18, Folder 692)
            - Military Commission. Abraham Lincoln Assassination Conspiracy Trial (Box 18, Folder 693)
              Identified, from left to right Thomas Maley Harris, David Hunter, August Valentine Kautz, James Adams Ekin, Lewis Wallace, and John Armor Brigham
            - Mitchell, Margaret Julia, actress (Box 18, Folder 694)
            - Nast, Thomas, caricaturist (Box 18, Folder 695)
            - Nicolay, John George, (3 photographic prints) (Box 18, Folder 696)
            - Peter II of Brazil (Box 18, Folder 697)
            - Phillips, Wendell (Box 18, Folder 698)
            - Pickett, George Edward, Confederate States of America (Box 18, Folder 699)
            - Pike, Albert (Box 18, Folder 700)
            - Rea, J. E. (Box 18, Folder 701)
            - Ream, Lavinia "Vinnie" Ellen, sculptor (Box 18, Folder 702)
            - Sigourney, Lydia Howard (née Huntley) (Box 18, Folder 703)
            - Slidell, Marie Mathilde Deslonde (Box 18, Folder 704)
            - Smith, Caleb Blood (Box 18, Folder 705)
              United States Secretary of the Interior
            - Speranza, Adelina, singer, circa 1859; (2 photographic prints) (Box 18, Folder 706)
            - Sprague, Katherine Jane Chase, (2 photographic prints) (Box 18, Folder 707)
            - Stratton, Lavinia Warren (Box 18, Folder 708)
            - Stuart, James Ewell Brown, Confederate States of America, (2 photographic prints) (Box 18, Folder 709)
            - Surratt, Elisabeth Susanna (Box 18, Folder 710)
              Daughter of Mary Elizabeth Eugenia Jenkins Surratt
            - Ten Eyck, John Conover, (2 photographic prints) (Box 18, Folder 711)
              United States Senator from New Jersey
            - Thomas, George Henry (Box 18, Folder 712)
            - Townsend, General Edward Davis (Box 18, Folder 713)
            - Vernon, Charles (Box 18, Folder 714)
            - Wallack family (Box 18, Folder 715)
              Identified from left to right, John Lester Wallack, Charles or Harry Wallack, and James William Wallack
            - Weston, Lucille, actress, (2 photographic prints) (Box 18, Folder 716)
            - Williams, Alpheus Starkey, and his staff (Box 18, Folder 717)
            - Woods, Charles Robert (Box 18, Folder 718)
            - Unidentified men, (5 photographic prints) (Box 18, Folder 719)
        - 1299 - James Noble Tyner, United States Postmaster General and United States Representative from Indiana
        - 1300-1303 - No photographic prints
        - 1304 - Julia Boggs Dent Grant
        - 1305 - Jesse Root Grant, Julia Boggs Dent Grant, and Ellen "Nellie" Wrenshall Grant (later Sartoris)
        - 1306 - Julia Boggs Dent Grant and Ellen 'Nellie" Wrenshall Grant (later Sartoris)
        - 1307 - Edith O. Gorman
        - 1308 - James Abram Garfield, probably with a granddaughter
        - 1309 - James Abram Garfield, probably with a granddaughter
        - 1310 - John Alexander Logan, United States Representative from Illinois and United States Senator from Illinois
        - 1311 - John Alexander Logan, United States Representative from Illinois, and United States Senator from Illinois; his wife, Mary Simmerson (Cunningham) Logan; daughter, Mary Elizabeth "Dollie" Logan (later Tucker), and son, Manning Alexander Logan (later John A. Logan II)
        - 1312 - Mary Simmerson (Cunningham) Logan; daughter, Mary Elizabeth "Dollie" Logan (later Tucker), and son, Manning Alexander Logan (later John A. Logan II)
        - 1313 - No photographic print
        - 1314 - Jesse Root Grant, Julia Boggs Dent Grant, and Ellen 'Nellie" Wrenshall Grant (later Sartoris)
        - 1315-1316 - No photographic prints
        - 1317 - Henry Laurens Dawes, United States Representative from Massachusetts and United States Senator from Massachusetts
        - 1318 - Sir Edward Thornton
        - 1319 - Marcus Mills "Brick" Pomeroy
        - 1320 - Charles Sumner, United States Senator from Massachusetts
        - 1321 - Sergeant Thomas P. "Boston" Corbett
        - 1322 - Unidentified man
          Misidentified as Judah Philip Benjamin
      - Leaf group No. 24, (3 photographic prints) (Box 16, Folder 636)
        - 1323 - Copy photograph of a painting of James Kearney
        - 1324 - John Clifford Pemberton, Confederate States of America
        - 1325 - No photographic print
        - 1326 - Copy photograph of an engraving of Chief Justice John Marshall
        - 1327-1346 - No photographic prints
      - Leaf group No. 25 (Box 16, Folder 637)
        - 1347-1399 - No photographic prints
    - Proof Book of Copy Photography, Bound volume with 162 pages containing 93 photographic prints (Box 17, Folder 638)
      An incomplete bound volume of mounted copy photographs of historical subjects. The boards and first 32 pages of the volume are missing. Each page originally contained one or two photographic prints, numbered and captioned in pencil or crayon inscriptions. Prints are missing from some pages, as noted below.
      - Image No. 22-24: No photographic prints
      - Image No. 25: Engraving, Inauguration of Washington. Robert Livingston administers the oath of office to George Washington. Left to right: Robert Livingston, Arthur St. Clair, Henry Knox, Roger Sherman, George Washington, Friedrich von Steuben and
      - Image No. 26: Engraving, President Rutherford B. Hayes and Cabinet. Left to right: Hayes, Secretary of the Treasury John Sherman, Secretary of the Navy Richard W. Thompson, Attorney General Charles Devens, Secretary of State William M. Evarts, Sec
      - Image No. 27: No photographic print
      - Image No. 28: Foundation for the House of Burgesses, Jamestown, Virginia
      - Image No. 29: Lincoln Memorial, Washington, District of Columbia
      - Image No. 30-31: No photographic print
      - Image No. 32: Lithograph, "Custer's Last Charge: Brevet Major-General George A. Custer, Lieutenant-Colonel 7th U.S. Cavalry," by Currier and Ives
      - Image No. 33: Arts Club of Washington, Washington, District of Columbia. Interior of an exhibit of paintings by Frederick Mortimer Lamb
      - Image No. 34: Copy photograph of engraving by Allanson, "Faneuil Hall, Boston," 1855
      - Image No. 36-37: No photographic print
      - Image No. 38: Wakefield, the birthplace house of George Washington, in Westmoreland County, Virginia, by Currier and Ives
      - Image No. 39: Engraving depicting portraits of United States presidents from George Washington to Zachary Taylor, engraved by J. Greenleaf, Boston, 1849
      - Image No. 40: Lithograph of Friedrich Wilhelm von Steuben
      - Image No. 41: Georgia, Savannah, 1734, after an engraving by Peter Gordon
      - Image No. 42: Lithograph, "View of Harpers Ferry, Virginia," by Currier & Ives
      - Image No. 43: Etching, Geese in Flight, probably by Frank Weston Benson
      - Image No. 44: Woodcut, "Emigrating from Connecticut to Eastern Ohio in 1805, distance 600 miles, time 90 days, number of passengers 10"
      - Image No. 45-48: No photographic prints
      - Image No. 49: Interior of the parlor at Monticello, Virginia
      - Image No. 50: Lithograph of Daniel Webster addressing the United States Senate, 1850
      - Image No. 51: No photographic print
      - Image No. 52: Lithograph of Elizabeth "Betsy" Griscom Ross
      - Image No. 53: Engraving, "The Rebels of '76, or the first announcement of the great declaration" Signers of the Declaration of Independence leaving Independence Hall, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania
      - Image No. 54: Interior of the Congressional Library in the United States Capitol Building, Washington, District of Columbia
      - Image No. 55: No photographic print
      - Image No. 56: Engraving, "Treaty Between William Penn and the Indians," by Weber & Co.
      - Image No. 57-59: No photographic prints
      - Image No. 60: Interior of the Dead Letter Office in the United States Post Office Building, Washington, District of Columbia
      - Image No. 61: Interior of the United States Fish Commission, Washington, District of Columbia
      - Image No. 62: No photographic print
      - Image No. 63: United States Fish Commission building, Washington, District of Columbia
      - Image No. 64-65: No photographic prints
      - Image No. 66: Toll house, between six and seven miles west of Cumberland, Maryland, near LaVale: Red Hill, photograph by H. Laney
      - Image No. 67: Reading the death warrant to Captain Henry Wirz on the execution scaffold, November 1865
      - Image No. 68: Lithograph, "Story of the Revolution," by Currier & Ives
      - Image No. 69-80: No photographic prints
      - Image No. 81: Old Capitol Prison, 1st and A Streets NE, Washington, District of Columbia
      - Image No. 82: No photographic print
      - Image No. 83: Interior of the Mechanics fresco in the United States Capitol Building, Washington, District of Columbia
      - Image No. 84: Interior of the Commerce fresco in the United States Capitol Building, Washington, District of Columbia
      - Image No. 85: Interior of the Science fresco in the United States Capitol Building, Washington, District of Columbia
      - Image No. 86: Interior of the Marine fresco in the United States Capitol Building, Washington, District of Columbia
      - Image No. 87: Interior of the Agriculture fresco in the United States Capitol Building, Washington, District of Columbia
      - Image No. 88: Interior detail of the doors to House of Representatives Chamber in the United States Capitol Building, Washington, District of Columbia
      - Image No. 89: Interior detail of the doors to House of Representatives Chamber in the United States Capitol Building, Washington, District of Columbia
      - Image No. 90: Detail of the Columbus Doors, "First Encounter with the Indians," in the United States Capitol Building, Washington, District of Columbia
      - Image No. 91: Interior detail from the doors to House of Representatives Chamber, in the United States Capitol Building, Washington, District of Columbia
      - Image No. 92: Detail of the Columbus Doors, "Entry of Columbus into Barcelona" in the United States Capitol Building, Washington, District of Columbia
      - Image No. 93: Detail of the Columbus Doors, "Audience at the Court of Ferdinand and Isabella" in the United States Capitol Building, Washington, District of Columbia
      - Image No. 94: Navy Yard, Washington, District of Columbia. Powder magazine and cannonballs
      - Image No. 95: Engraving of the Statehouse, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania
      - Image No. 96: Engraving of Old Courthouse, York, Pennsylvania
      - Image No. 97: Engraving of Federal Hall, New York, New York
      - Image No. 98: Engraving of Old Courthouse, Trenton, New Jersey
      - Image No. 99: Engraving of Congress House, Baltimore, Maryland
      - Image No. 100: Table on which the Declaration of Independence was signed in 1776
      - Image No. 101: Engraving of Nassau Hall, Princeton, New Jersey
      - Image No. 102-103: No photographic prints
      - Image No. 104: Engraving of Fraunces Tavern, New York, New York
      - Image No. 105: Lithograph of the State-House in Philadelphia, 1776, by John Serz
      - Image No. 106: No photographic print
      - Image No. 107: Interior of the East Room of the White House, Washington, District of Columbia
      - Image No. 108: Statue of James A. Garfield, by John Quincy Adams Ward, at Maryland Avenue NE and 1st Street NE, Washington, District of Columbia
      - Image No. 109-112: No photographic prints
      - Image No. 113: Engraving depicting a visit of Pontiac (Obwandiyag) to Major Henry Gladwin
      - Image No. 114: Steamboat and sailboats at a dock
      - Image No. 115: Engraving of the Rocket, an early steam locomotive invented by George Stephenson
      - Image No. 116: Engraving of the model steam carriage invented by William Symington
      - Image No. 117-118: No photographic prints
      - Image No. 119: Obelisk monument to George Washington at Wakefield, Westmoreland County, Virginia
      - Image No. 120-121: No photographic prints
      - Image No. 122: Lithograph, "The Brave Boy of Waxhaws," by Currier & Ives
      - Image No. 123: Interior of the National Statuary Hall, showing The Car of History clock, by Carlo Franzoni, United States Capitol Building, Washington, District of Columbia.
      - Image No. 124: Exterior portrait of George Brinton McClellan and his staff
      - Image No. 125: Interior of the Army Medical Museum and Library, Independence Avenue SE and 7th Street SE, Washington, District of Columbia
      - Image No. 126: No photographic print
      - Image No. 127: Independence Hall, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania
      - Image No. 128: Painting, Christopher Columbus at Court on his Return, by Ricardo Balaca
      - Image No. 129: Lithograph, "Tocsin of Liberty: Rung by the State House Bell, (Independence Hall) Philadelphia, July 4th, 1776," by Currier & Ives
      - Image No. 130: Sculpture, The Mountain Man, by Frederic Remington
      - Image No. 131: No photographic print
      - Image No. 132: Composite print of Robert E. Lee and his staff, 1866, by Rockwell and Cowell
      - Image No. 133-136: No photographic prints
      - Image No. 137: Composite of the House of Representatives in the Thirty-eighth Congress, 1863-1865
      - Image No. 138: Composite of the House of Representatives in the Thirty-eighth Congress, 1863-1865, with index
      - Image No. 139: Composite of the House of Representatives in the Thirty-seventh Congress, 1860
      - Image No. 140: Composite of the House of Representatives in the Thirty-seventh Congress, 1860, with index
      - Image No. 141: Lithograph, "John Hancock's Defiance," by Currier & Ives
      - Image No. 142: No photographic print
      - Image No. 143: Painting of a nude girl standing in water
      - Image No. 144: Engraving depicting Patrick Henry
      - Image No. 145: Sculpture, Grief (Adams Monument), by Augustus Saint-Gaudens, in Rock Creek Cemetery, Washington, District of Columbia
      - Image No. 146: No photographic print
      - Image No. 148: Painting, Landing of Christopher Columbus, by John Vanderlyn
      - Image No. 149: Painting, Discovery of the Mississippi, by William H. Powell
      - Image No. 150: Painting, Embarkation of the Pilgrims, by Robert W. Weir
      - Image No. 151: Painting. Signing the Declaration of Independence, by John Trumbull
      - Image No. 152: Painting, General George Washington Resigning His Commission, by John Trumbull
      - Image No. 153: Painting, Surrender of General Burgoyne, by John Trumbull
      - Image No. 154: Painting, Surrender of Lord Cornwallis, by John Trumbull
      - Image No. 155: Painting, Baptism of Pocahontas, by John Gadsby Chapman
      - Image No. 156: Statue of Ethan Allen by Larkin G. Mead in National Statuary Hall, United States Capitol Building, Washington, District of Columbia
      - Image No. 157-159: No photographic prints
      - Image No. 160: Painting, The Battle of Chapultepec (Storming of Chapultepec), by James Walker
      - Image No. 161: Statue of Alexander Hamilton sculpted by Horatio Stone
      - Image No. 162: Statues in National Statuary Hall, United States Capitol Building, Washington, District of Columbia
      - Image No. 163: Engraving depicting Benjamin Franklin being presented at the French royal court
      - Image No. 164: Engraving of the wedding of President Grover Cleveland and Frances Folsom, by J. E. Sharp
      - Image No. 165: Engraving depicting the inaugural ball of President Grover Cleveland
      - Image No. 166-170: No photographic prints
      - Image No. 171: Engraving depicting colonists with guns walking toward a wooden stockade with cannon mounted on the roof
      - Image No. 172: Lithograph, "Pioneer Fire Fighters" by the Donaldson Litho Company, Newport, Kentucky
      - Image No. 173-175: No photographic prints
      - Image No. 176: Lithograph depicting a view of Baltimore, Maryland, probably from Federal Hill
      - Image No. 177-179: No photographic prints
      - Image No. 180: Painting a girl with nine boys by John George Brown
      - Image No. 181-183: No photographic prints
      - Image No. 184: Statues and paintings in National Statuary Hall, United States Capitol Building, Washington, District of Columbia
      - Image No. 185-200: No photographic prints
  - Original Photographs, (286 photographic prints)
    Photographic prints created by the studio from original negatives, including images created by the Mathew B. Brady Studio.
    Series arranged with prints originally created by the Mathew B. Brady Studio, consisting of portraits followed by photographs of interiors and exteriors, followed by prints and other photographic materials created by the Levin Corbin Handy studio, stereographs, and lantern slides.
    - Photographic Prints of Images by the Mathew B. Brady Studio, (179 photographic prints)
      Reprints by the studio of Levin Corbin Handy of images created by the studio of Mathew B. Brady. The photographs primarily depict locations, persons, and events of the American Civil War, as well as some antebellum studio portraits.
      Arranged alphabetically by geographical location of the subject, with studio portraits arranged alphabetically by the surname of the subject at the end.
      - District of Columbia, Washington
        - 15th Street NW and Pennsylvania Avenue NW. Oxen team pulling a cannon (Box 19, Folder 720)
        - 3rd Massachusetts Heavy Artillery, Company F, (2 photographic prints) (Box 19, Folder 721)
        - Anderson Cottage Lincoln's Summer Home, (5 photographic prints) (Box 19, Folder 722)
        - Carver Hospital (Box 19, Folder 723)
        - Exterior portrait of officers of the United States Treasury Battalion with the uncompleted Washington Monument in the background (Box 19, Folder 724)
        - Ford's Theatre (Box 19, Folder 725)
        - Ford's Theatre. Interior, (2 photographic prints) (Box 19, Folder 726)
        - Fort Totten. Interior (Box 19, Folder 727)
        - Funeral procession of Abraham Lincoln on Pennsylvania Avenue (Box 19, Folder 728)
        - Grand Review of the Army, the Presidential reviewing stand, 1865 May (Box 19, Folder 729)
        - Harewood Hospital. Soldiers in ranks on parade, possibly the 12th Michigan Infantry (Box 19, Folder 730)
        - Navy Yard
          - Adjusting the rope for the execution of Henry Wirz, 1865 Nov 10 (Box 19, Folder 731)
          - Exterior portrait of Hartman Richter on the deck of the USS Saugus, (2 photographic prints) (Box 19, Folder 732)
        - Religious service being conducted by Thomas Scully, Chaplain for the 9th Massachusetts Infantry, 1861-1862 (Box 19, Folder 733)
        - Washington Monument under construction, circa 1859-1876 (Box 19, Folder 734)
      - Georgia, Atlanta
        - Confederate fortifications, (2 photographic prints) (Box 19, Folder 735)
        - Federal Fort No. 7, railroad two miles southwest of Atlanta, (2 photographic prints) (Box 19, Folder 736)
      - Kentucky, Tennessee, and Virginia, Cumberland Gap (Box 19, Folder 737)
      - Maryland, Sharpsburg, Vicinity
        - Antietam bridge (Box 19, Folder 738)
        - Artillery (Box 19, Folder 739)